Guide to the People's College records, 1848-1880.
People's College records,1848-1880.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
People's College records, 1848-1880.
1138
People's College (Montour Falls, N.Y.)
1.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, scrapbooks, financial documents, academic papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Letters, scrapbooks, pamphlets, and other material relating to the establishment of the college in Montour Falls (then Havana), Schuyler County, New York; includes correspondence of the founder, Harrison Howard. Also records relating to administration, finance, and construction, 1856-1880, including land transactions, articles of agreement, building plans, specifications, supplies, labor, costs, and receipts; and educational papers, 1850-1864, including letters, teachers' applications, recommendations, minutes, presidents' reports, resolutions, and lists of students, faculty, and trustees. Includes a letter from Horace Greeley dated February 26, 1859 to the Treasurer of People's College. Also, John Hay, Assistant Private Secretary, Executive Mansion, Washington, D.C. to Charles Cooke, June 26, 1863, enclosing the Horace Greeley resolution relating to the People's College Convention. Also copy of the Horace Greeley resolution relating to The People's College Convention, November 1, 1852. Additional correspondents include Edward Hitchcock, Mark Hopkins, Theodore D. Woolsey, and the Geneva Medical College.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Letters, scrapbooks, pamphlets, and other material relating to the establishment of the college in Montour Falls (then Havana), Schuyler County, New York; includes correspondence of the founder, Harrison Howard. Also records relating to administration, finance, and construction, 1856-1880, including land transactions, articles of agreement, building plans, specifications, supplies, labor, costs, and receipts; and educational papers, 1850-1864, including letters, teachers' applications, recommendations, minutes, presidents' reports, resolutions, and lists of students, faculty, and trustees. Includes a letter from Horace Greeley dated February 26, 1859 to the Treasurer of People's College. Also, John Hay, Assistant Private Secretary, Executive Mansion, Washington, D.C. to Charles Cooke, June 26, 1863, enclosing the Horace Greeley resolution relating to the People's College Convention. Also copy of the Horace Greeley resolution relating to The People's College Convention, November 1, 1852. Additional correspondents include Edward Hitchcock, Mark Hopkins, Theodore D. Woolsey, and the Geneva Medical College.
SUBJECTS
Names:
People's College (Montour Falls, N.Y.); Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872.; Hay, John.; Hitchcock, Edward, 1828-1911.; Hopkins, Mark, 1802-1887.; Howard, Harrison.; Woolsey, Theodore Dwight, 1801-1889; Cook Academy (Montour Falls, N.Y.); Geneva Medical College (Geneva, N.Y.); People's College (Montour Falls, N.Y.)--Buildings.
Subjects:
Education--New York (State)--Montour Falls.; Universities and colleges--New York (State)--Montour Falls.
Places:
Schuyler County (N.Y.)--Intellectual life--19th century.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Howard Papers, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Plans and Charter, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Address by Prof. J.B. Turner, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- W.L. Hewitt Correspondence, 1893-1895 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Misc. Manuscripts, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Misc. W.W. Folwell Papers, 1921-1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Morrill Act, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Harrison Howard's sketch of the establishment of the People's College, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brewer's History, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Howard Papers, Oct.-Dec. 1852 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Howard Papers, April-Sept. 1852 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Howard Papers, Jan.-March 1852 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- (No Title), Not Dated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Howard Papers, 1848-1851 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Howard Papers, 1858-1859 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- (No Title), 1859, 1863, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Howard Papers, Jan.-May 1857 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Howard Papers, June-Dec. 1857 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Howard Papers, Oct.-Dec 1856 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Howard Papers, Sept.-Dec. 1855-Jan.-Sept. 1856 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Howard Papers, March-Aug. 1855 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Howard Papers, Nov.-Dec. 1854-Jan.-Feb. 1855 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Howard Papers, June-Oct. 1854 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Howard Papers, Jan.-May 1854 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Howard Papers, Sept.-Dec. 1853 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Howard Papers, July-Aug. 1853 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Howard Papers, Aug. 24, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Howard Papers, Jan.-June 1853 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Howard Papers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Howard Papers, 1860-1875 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Harrison Howard Reference Book, 1856 (Box 3)
- Harrison Howard Scrap book, Not Dated (Box 3)
- Papers Relating to People's College, Not Dated (Box 3)
- Public Exercises: Mapping of the Corner Stone, 1958 (Box 3)
- Havana Journal, 1958 (Box 3)
- The Watkins Republican, 1958 (Box 3)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, June-Oct.1857 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, 1856 and before (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Oct.-Dec. 1857 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Jan.-April 1858 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, May-Aug. 30, 1858 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Sept. 1858 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Oct. 1858 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Nov. 1858 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Dec., 1858, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Jan.-Aug. 30, 1859 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Sept.-Dec. 1859 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, 1860 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Jan-April 1861 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Nov.-Dec. 1861, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Sept.-Oct. 1861 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, May-Aug. 1861 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Jan-April 1862 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, May-Aug. 1862 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Sept.-Dec. 1862 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Jan-April 1863 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, May-Aug. 1863 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Sept.-Dec. 1863 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Jan.-June 1864 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, July-Dec. 1864 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Receipts, 1853-1880 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Administration, Finance, Construction, Undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Educational Papers, 1850 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Educational Papers, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Educational Papers, 1858 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Educational Papers, June 6-June 14 1859 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Educational Papers, Aug.1-Nov.30 1859 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Educational Papers, 1860 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Educational Papers, Jan.-Oct. 1861 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Educational Papers, Jan.-Nov. 1862 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Educational Papers, Jan.-Nov. 1863 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Educational Papers, Feb.-May 1863 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Educational Papers, April-June 1864 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Educational Papers, July-Nov. 1864 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Educational Papers, Undated (Box 4, Folder 42)